Did you know that Google name is originally a play on the word Googol,
أكنت تعلم أن اسم Google هو في الأصل تلاعب لفظي على كلمة Googol،
which is a mathematical term for a massive number equal to one followed by 100 zeros?
وهي مصطلح رياضي لعدد هائل جداً يساوي واحد متبوع بمئة صفر؟
Google liked it so much because it seemed like
أحبته Google كثيراً لأنه بدا
there was as many web pages over the Internet.
أن هذا هو عدد الصفحات الإلكترونية على الإنترنت.
In fact, Googol is so massive that there is
في الواقع، إن Googol هائل جداً
no numerical data type in Java that can actually store it.
لدرجة أنه لا يوجد أي نوع بيانات عددي في Java يستطيع حفظه.
Even a long data type can store only a number up to two to the 63,
حتى نوع بيانات طويل يمكنه أن يحفظ عدداً لا يتعدى 2 أس 63،
which is merely a 19 digit long number.
وهو عدد فيه 19 رقماً فقط.
In fact, there are far less electrons in the entire universe than one single Googol.
في الواقع، هناك إلكترونات أقل بكثير في الكون بأكمله من رقم Googol واحد.
On the other hand, we can store the number as a string of
لكن من جهة أخرى، يمكننا حفظ العدد على أنه سلسلة أحرف
it can actually fit in a string in Java.
فيمكن بالفعل أن يتم احتوائها في سلسلة في Java.
We can't really do any mathematical operation with it since it's stored in a string,
لا يمكننا القيام بأي عمليات رياضية بها بما أنها محفوظة في سلسلة،
but we can use the string to do other stuff like printed out for example.
لكن يمكننا استخدام السلسلة للقيام بأمور أخرى كطباعتها مثلاً.
However, typing down 101 characters seems a bit tedious.
لكن كتابة 100 حرف وحرف تبدو مضجرة قليلاً.
So why don't we use a while loop to build that string for us?
فلماذا لا نستخدم حلقة while لإنشاء تلك السلسة لنا؟
We start with initializing the string with just one,
نبدأ بتعيين قيمة السلسلة بواحد،
and then we can concatenate a zero string to it inside a while loop.
ثم يمكننا وصل سلسلة بصفر معها داخل حلقة while.
The while loop would keep checking if the length of the string is still less than 101,
ستستمر حلقة while بتفحص ما إن كان طول السلسلة لا يزال أقل من 101،
and it would keep concatenating another zero to it until the length becomes 101.
وستستمر في وصل صفراً آخر معها حتى يصبح الطول 101.
So we need to keep track of the string length.
علينا إذن متابعة طول السلسلة.
For that, we declare and initialize a variable len,
لفعل ذلك، نعرّف متغير len ونعين قيمته،
which is an integer and we assign it the value of googol.length.
وهو عدد حقيقي، ونعين له قيمة googol.length".
The function length calculates the length of
الدالة length تحسب طول تلك السلسلة
that string and returns it and stores it into the variable len.
وتعرض النتيجة وتحفظها في المتغير len.
Then we also update that variable inside the loop so it's
ثم نحدّث أيضاً ذلك المتغير داخل الحلقة
always keeping track of the length of the string googol.
بحيث يتعقب طول سلسلة googol دائماً.
Can you think of what the while condition should be?
أيمكنك معرفة ما ينبغي أن تكون حالة while؟
Remember, we need to keep iterating over this loop for as long as
تذكر أنه علينا الاستمرار في تكرار هذه الحلقة